microstrategy.com 2015-12-30

# Privacy Policy | MicroStrategy

##  MicroStrategy Website Privacy Policy

_Last modified: April 10, 2013_

This Website Privacy Policy describes how MicroStrategy Incorporated (“MicroStrategy”) may collect personal information from you on the microstrategy.com website (the “Site”), the types of information we may collect, how we may use the information, how we protect the information and with whom we may share it. In addition, we tell you how you can ask us to (i) access, change or not use the personal information we maintain about you, (ii) withdraw consent you previously provided to us, (iii) refrain from sending you certain communications, and (iv) answer questions you may have about our privacy practices.

Please note that this Privacy Policy only applies to this Site and that other MicroStrategy-affiliated websites are subject to their own privacy policies. Please also note that if you are accessing this Site from a country in the European Economic Area* or Switzerland, your use of this Site is subject to the privacy policy found here.

###  How We May Collect or Receive Information from You

We may collect or receive your personal information from you through your use of the Site in various ways. You may choose to submit your personal information and other information to us through various communication channels provided on the "Contact Us" webpage of the Site, for example, by email, or telephone. You may also choose to submit your personal information to us by email or through online forms in connection with activities such as account creation, use of MicroStrategy services, downloads of our software, inquiries about becoming a MicroStrategy partner, inquiries about jobs at MicroStrategy, job applications, conference or training registrations, purchases of products and services and requests for support

####  Cookies

In addition, when you visit the Site, we may collect certain information by automated means, such as cookies. A "cookie" is a file that websites send to a visitor's computer or other Internet-connected device to uniquely identify the visitor's browser or to store information or settings on the device. The information we collect in this manner enables us to better serve you when you return to our site- for example, it can "remember" your email address to save you having to enter it manually upon your return. We also use cookies to track responses to our marketing materials, such as emails and online advertisements. Your browser may tell you how to be notified when you receive certain types of cookies or how to restrict or disable certain types of cookies. For more information about MicroStrategy’s own cookies, please see “How to work with Cookies.”

The Site may also feature cookies associated with certain unaffiliated companies. For example, we partner with other companies to provide you with connections to certain social networks, such as Facebook and Twitter, and to provide you with additional features such as YouTube. By engaging with such other companies’ sites, for instance, by clicking the Facebook "Like" button found on our Site, such companies may place session or persistent cookies on your device. The use of these cookies is subject to such companies’ own cookie policies, which MicroStrategy strongly recommends you review before you use the Site.

####  Web Analytics and Interest-Based Advertising

We may use web analytics services on this site, such as those of Google Analytics. The service providers that administer these services use technologies such as cookies to help us analyze how visitors use the site. The information collected through these means (including IP address) is disclosed to or collected directly by these service providers, who use the information to evaluate use of the website or for advertising purposes, as described below.

Some of our online advertising takes place through Google Display Advertising. As part of this program, we use Google Analytics features such as Retargeting. In connection with that feature and others offered by ad networks, we and the operators of ad networks, including Google, may use third-party cookies (such as the DoubleClick cookie) – and in some cases first-party cookies (such as the Google Analytics cookie) – to inform, optimize, and serve ads across the internet based on a user’s past visits to our website.

You can opt out of Google Analytics for Display Advertising or customize Google Display Network ads using the Google [Ads Preferences Manager](http://www.google.com/ads/preferences). To disable Google Analytics in general, please download the browser add-on for the deactivation of Google Analytics provided by Google at <http://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout>. To learn more about other ad networks, including how to opt out, [click here](http://www.networkadvertising.org/choices/).

###  The Types of Information We May Collect

The information you may submit to us when you use the Site will generally consist of your name and contact information, such as your email address, phone number, and physical address. We may request this information from you in connection with activities such as account creation, use of services, downloads of our software, inquiries about becoming a MicroStrategy partner, inquiries about jobs at MicroStrategy, job applications, conference or training registrations, purchases of products and services and requests for support. In connection with job inquiries and job applications we may require additional personal information from you, such as your education history. In connection with your purchases of products and services we may also collect billing information from you.

Via the cookies mentioned above under the section "How We May Collect or Receive Information from You," we may also collect information regarding your website usage, IP-address, browser type, email address and operating system.

Please note that information that you upload into MicroStrategy's cloud in connection with your use of our MicroStrategy Express product offered on the Site is not addressed by this Privacy Policy but is instead subject to the terms of the MicroStrategy Express Master Subscription Agreement that you must enter with us prior to using MicroStrategy Express.

###  How We Use The Information We Collect

We may use the information we collect from you to:

  * provide services to you;
  * provide you with notice of product releases, special events, trainings, promotions or other matters relevant to you;
  * provide technical support and respond to your inquiries;
  * improve the level of service you receive from us;
  * prevent you from having to re-enter your personal information on future visits to the Site;
  * process your payments and purchases;
  * operate, evaluate and improve our business (including developing new products and services; enhancing and improving our services; managing our communications; analyzing our products; performing data analytics; and performing accounting, auditing and other internal functions);
  * detect and prevent fraud and other unauthorized activity; and
  * comply with applicable legal requirements, relevant industry standards and our policies.

We also may use the information we obtain about you in other ways for which we provide specific notice at the time of collection.

###  How We May Share Information

We may disclose information about you (i) to our third party service providers; (ii) to other MicroStrategy group companies; (iii) if we are required to do so by law, regulation or legal process (such as a court order or subpoena), (iv) in response to requests by government agencies, such as law enforcement authorities, (v) when we believe disclosure is necessary or appropriate to prevent physical harm or financial loss or in connection with an investigation of suspected or actual illegal activity or (vi) in any other case, with your consent. We also reserve the right to transfer any information we have about you in the event we sell or transfer all or a portion of our business or assets, including in the event of a reorganization, dissolution or liquidation.

###  How We Protect Personal Information

We maintain administrative, technical and physical safeguards designed to protect the personal information you provide against accidental, unlawful or unauthorized destruction, loss, alteration, access, disclosure or use.

###  Links to Other Websites

The Site may contain links to websites maintained by third parties, whose information and privacy practices differ from ours, including, for example, websites that process online payments. We are not responsible or liable for the content of any such websites, any use of such websites or the information or privacy practices employed by the providers of such websites. We encourage you to read the privacy statements of all third party websites before using such websites or submitting any personal information or any other information on or through such websites.

###  Access and Correction

To request a copy of the personal information we maintain about you, update or correct inaccuracies in that information, or request that we remove your personal information from our systems and stop contacting you at any time by sending an email to [info@microstrategy.com](mailto:info@microstrategy.com) that details your request and includes your exact name, physical address and email address.

###  Updates To Our Website Privacy Policy

MicroStrategy reserves the right to change this Website Privacy Policy at any time. If we change this Website Privacy Policy, we will post a prominent notice on the Site to notify you of any significant changes and indicate at the top of the policy when it was most recently update. We encourage you to review the Website Privacy Policy regularly.

###  How To Contact Us

If you have any comments or inquiries about this Website Privacy Policy, if you would like to update information we have about you or to exercise your rights, you may contact us by sending an email to [info@microstrategy.com](mailto:info@microstrategy.com) or by sending regular mail to the following address:

Attn: Office of the General Counsel  
MicroStrategy Incorporated  
1850 Towers Crescent Plaza  
Tysons Corner, Virginia 22182

* The European Economic Area is composed of the following countries: Austria, Belgium, Bulgaria, Cyprus, Czech Republic, Denmark, Estonia, Finland, France, Germany, Greece, Hungary, Iceland, Republic of Ireland, Italy, Latvia, Liechtenstein, Lithuania, Luxembourg, Malta, The Netherlands, Norway, Poland, Portugal, Romania, Slovakia, Slovenia, Spain, Sweden and UK
